A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Special Collections Publications FA1395
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Fund for Adult Education (FAE) Publications, 1934-2010; 3
  - Basic Issues of Man Volume 2 - Man and Society: Problems and Historical Experience, C. Jay Smith, Jr., 1961 (Box 41, Folder 419)
  - Basic Issues of Man Volume 3 - Political Perspectives, George S. Parthemos, 1961 (Box 41, Folder 420)
  - Basic Issues of Man Volume 4 - Creativity and the Arts, George O. Marshall, Jr. Editor, 1961 (Box 41, Folder 421)
  - Basic Issues of Man Volume 5 - Scientific Life of Man, Jonathan J. Westfall, 1961 (Box 41, Folder 422)
  - Basic Issues of Man Volume 6 - Philosophical Perspectives, George L. Newsome, Jr. (Box 41, Folder 423)
  - Great Men and Great Issues in Our American Heritage: A Series of Adult Discussion Programs, 1952 (Box 42, Folder 424)
  - Great Men and Great Issues in Our American Heritage pamphlet, undated (Box 42, Folder 425)
  - How to Organize and Manage a 'Great Men and Great Issues' Film-Discussion Project, 1952 (Box 42, Folder 426)
  - A Discussion Leader's Manual: Great Men and Great Issues in Our American Heritage, 1952 (Box 42, Folder 427)
  - Great Men and Great Issues in Our American Heritage, Film Council of America pamphlet, undated (Box 42, Folder 428)
  - American Heritage Project of the American Library Association, 1953-1954 (Box 42, Folder 429)
  - An Introduction to the Humanities: A Study Discussion Program for Adults, 1958 (Box 42, Folder 430)
  - An Introduction to the Humanities: Book of Readings and Music Supplement, 1955 (Box 42, Folder 431)
  - An Introduction to the Humanities: A Guide for Discussion Leaders, Prepared by Members of the Humanities Staff of the College of the University of Chicago, 1958 (Box 42, Folder 432)
  - An Introduction to the Humanities: Participants Manual, Including a Guide for Discussion Leaders, 1955 (Box 42, Folder 433)
  - Great Issues in American Politics: A Series of Study and Discussion Programs for Adult Groups - Part 1, 1956 (Box 42, Folder 434)
  - Great Issues in American Politics: A Series of Study and Discussion Programs for Adult Groups - Part 2, undated (Box 43, Folder 435)
  - Great Issues in American Politics: Some Suggestions About the Discussion, undated (Box 43, Folder 436)
  - Great Issues in American Politics: An Experience in Political Debate and Discussion, undated (Box 43, Folder 437)
  - Great Issues in American Politics, Prepared by Dr. Richard Hofstadter, Professor of History, Columbia University - Study-Discussion Program Materials, undated (Box 43, Folder 438)
  - Labor's Public Education: A Symposium Sponsored by National Institute of Labor Education, 1960 (Box 43, Folder 439)
  - Labor Education: A Study Report on Needs, Programs, and Approaches, Joseph Mire, Inter-University Labor Education Committee, 1956 (Box 43, Folder 440)
  - Learning and Society: Readings in Canadian Adult Education, J. R. Kidd, Canadian Association for Adult Education, 1963 (Box 43, Folder 441)
  - Public School Adult Education: A Guide for Administrators, A Publication of the National Association of Public School Adult Educators, 1956 (Box 43, Folder 442)
  - Toward the Liberally Educated Executive, Edited by Robert A. Goldwin and Charles A. Nelson, The Fund for Adult Education, 1959 (Box 43, Folder 443)
  - The Use of Television in Education: Report of the New York Educational Television Institute, Lester W. Ingalls, Jr., 1953 March (Box 44, Folder 444)
  - The Power to Govern: An Examination of the Separation of Powers in the American System Government, 1957 (Box 44, Folder 445)
  - University of the Northern Plains: A History of the University of North Dakota, 1883-1958, Louis G. Geiger (Box 44, Folder 446)
  - With All Deliberate Speed: Segregation-Desegregation in Southern Schools, Prepared by Staff Members and Associates of Southern Education Reporting Service, Edited by Don Shoemaker, 1957 (Box 44, Folder 447)
  - Second Southwest Seminar in Public Responsibility, University of Oklahoma, 1960 December 7-10 (Box 44, Folder 448)
  - Who Are The Puerto Rican Pupils in the New York City Public Schools?, Samuel M. Goodman, Lorraine K. Diamond, and David J. Fox, Puerto Rican Study Research Report, Board of Education, City of New York, 1956 (Box 45, Folder 449)
  - Young People and Citizenship, Edward B. Olds and Eric Josephson, National Social Welfare Assembly, New York, 1953 (Box 45, Folder 450)
  - Readings in American Foreign Policy, Volume One to Volume Three, For Sessions 1 to 10, American Foundation for Political Education, 1952 (Box 45, Folder 451-453)
  - Readings in American Democracy Volumes 1 & 2 For Sessions I-X, American Foundation for Political Education, 1958 (Box 45, Folder 454-455)
  - Voluntary Listener-Sponsorship: A Report to Educational Broadcasters on the Experiment at KPFA, Berkeley, California, Lewis Hill, 1958 (Box 45, Folder 456)
  - 1951-1961: A Ten Year Report of the Fund for Adult Education (Box 45, Folder 457)
  - Participant's Manual for the Adult Discussion Series: You and Your Community, The American Community Project, New York University, 1954 (Box 46, Folder 458)
  - 1 - The Community Then and Now: Essays for the Experimental Discussion Series: You and Your Community, The American Community Project, New York University, 1954 (Box 46, Folder 459)
  - 2 - The Community and Its Role in the World Today: Essays for the Experimental Discussion Series: You and Your Community, The American Community Project, New York University, 1954 (Box 46, Folder 460)
  - 3 - People Are Important: Essays for the Experimental Discussion Series: You and Your Community, The American Community Project, New York University, 1954 (Box 46, Folder 461)
  - 4 - Unfinished Business in the Community: Essays for the Experimental Discussion Series: You and Your Community, The American Community Project, New York University, 1954 (Box 46, Folder 462)
  - 5 - Community Resources: Essays for the Experimental Discussion Series: You and Your Community, The American Community Project, New York University, 1954 (Box 46, Folder 463)
  - 6 - Cooperation Builds a Community: Essays for the Experimental Discussion Series: You and Your Community, The American Community Project, New York University, 1954 (Box 46, Folder 464)
  - 7 - Obstacles to Healthy Community Growth: Essays for the Experimental Discussion Series: You and Your Community, The American Community Project, New York University, 1954 (Box 46, Folder 465)
  - 8 - The Future of the Community: Essay for the Experimental Discussion Series: You and Your Community, The American Community Project, New York University, 1954 (Box 46, Folder 466)
  - Leader's Guide for the Adult Discussion Series: You and Your Community, The American Community Foundation, New York University, Eleanor Eaton and Ruth Bornn, 1954 (Box 46, Folder 467)
  - You and Your Community: A Guide for Participants and Discussion Leaders, 1955 (Box 46, Folder 468)
  - Lost Along the Way, Filmstrip Script for Session I, American Community Project, undated (Box 46, Folder 469)
  - The Community...and...It's Role in the World Today, Script to a Recording By Norman Cousins, Session II, American Community Project, undated (Box 46, Folder 470)
  - Unfinished Business, Filmstrip Script for Session IV, American Community Project, undated (Box 46, Folder 471)
  - Unlimited Resources, Filmstrip Script, Session V, American Community Project, undated (Box 46, Folder 472)
  - Sioux Falls Story, Filmstrip Script for Session VI, American Community Project, undated (Box 46, Folder 473)
  - Roadblocks Along the Way, Script Read by Elmore McKee for Session VII, American Community Project, undated (Box 46, Folder 474)
  - 1 - The Community, Then and Now, Essays for the Adult Discussion Series, You and Your Community, 1955 (Box 46, Folder 475)
  - 2 - People are Important, Essays for the Adult Discussion Series, You and Your Community, 1955 (Box 46, Folder 476)
  - 3 - Unfinished Business in the Community, Essays for the Adult Discussion Series, You and Your Community, 1955 (Box 46, Folder 477)
  - 4 - Community Resources, Essays for the Adult Discussion Series, You and Your Community, 1955 (Box 46, Folder 478)
  - 5 - Cooperation Builds a Community, Essays for the Adult Discussion Series, You and Your Community, 1955 (Box 46, Folder 479)
  - 6 - Obstacles to Healthy Community Growth, Essays for the Adult Discussion Series, You and Your Community, 1955 (Box 46, Folder 480)
  - 7 - The Community and Its Role in the World Today, Essays for the Adult Discussion Series, You and Your Community, 1955 (Box 46, Folder 481)
  - 8 - The Future of the Community, Essay for the Adult Discussion Series, You and Your Community, 1955 (Box 46, Folder 482)
  - Correspondence: Indian Education, Secondary Education Council, 1954-1958 (Box 46, Folder 483)
  - Basic Issues in Education, Francis Keppel, 1958 May 22 (Box 46, Folder 484)
    An address delivered under the sponsorship of the Adult Education Council of the Chattanooga Area as part of its Basic American Issues project
  - The Free University: Its Role in Education for Public Responsibility and the Future of Our Free Society and the Free World, C. Scott Fletcher, 1961 January 18 (Box 46, Folder 485)
    An Address before the Senate, Syracuse University, Syracuse, NY, Published by University College of Syracuse University
  - Test Cities Project: Quarterly Cities Project, 1954 January-March (Box 46, Folder 486)
  - Memorandum for the Executive Committee of the Trustees of the Ford Foundation on The Fund for Adult Education, #14, 1954 March 19-20 (Box 46, Folder 487)
  - Alumni Education for Public Responsibility, Arden House Conference, 1961 February 23-25 (Box 46, Folder 488)
  - High-Level Manpower in Colombia: A Market Analysis, Published Under the Auspices of the Ford Foundation, 1968-1969 (Box 46, Folder 489)
  - An Essay: Some Principles of Leadership Development for Training Leaders in Informal Educational Organizations, Esther Washington Reed, 1962 (Box 47, Folder 490)
  - A Humanistic Re-Education for the Corporate Executive, Morse Peckham, No. 29, 1957 (Box 47, Folder 491)
  - Report and Recommendations to the Fund for Adult Education by The National Committee on Study Grants, 1953 (Box 47, Folder 492)
  - The Fund for Adult Education, Reports to Board of Directors - I. Educational Effectiveness of Study-Discussion Groups; II. Educational Television, 1958 October (Box 47, Folder 493)
  - Background Material Fund for Adult Education, Statement by the Board of Trustees of the Ford Foundation, 1954 May 21-22 (Box 47, Folder 494)
  - The Fund for Adult Education, Projection by Percentages for Use of Funds to Advance Liberal Adult Education in the USA Through December 31, 1961, Preliminary Staff Suggestions (Box 47, Folder 495)
  - Three Year Report to the Fund for Adult Education from the Foreign Policy Association, 1955 September 23 (Box 47, Folder 496)
  - Terminal Report to the Fund for Adult Education by The Foreign Policy Association, 1956 (Box 47, Folder 497)
  - Recommendation to the Fund for Adult Education by Development Committee on Internships, Fellowships and Scholarships in the Mass Media, 1953 (?) (Box 47, Folder 498)
  - The Development Committee's Work - One Year Later, 1953 (Box 47, Folder 499)
    Development Committee on Internships, Scholarships, and Fellowships
  - Progress Report on the Experimental Film Discussion Project of The Fund for Adult Education, 1952 April (Box 47, Folder 500)
  - Educational Television and Radio Center, 1952-1956: A Report from the Educational Television and Radio Center to The Fund for Adult Education, 1957 February 15 (Box 47, Folder 501)
  - Delivering on a Promise to Advance Human Welfare (3 copies), 2006 (Box 48, Folder 502)
  - Design for Pakistan: A Report on Assistance to the Pakistan Planning Commission by the Ford Foundation and Harvard University, 1965 (Box 48, Folder 503)
  - Collaborations that Count: Working for Democracy in Devolutionary Times, 2000 July (Box 48, Folder 504)
  - Academe: Bulletin of the American Association of University Professors, 2006 July-August (Box 48, Folder 505)
  - The Educational Endowment Series: The Developing Law of Endowment Funds: "The Law and the Lore" Revisited: A Report to the Ford Foundation by William L. Cary and Craig B. Bright, 1974 (Box 48, Folder 506)
  - World Politics Program: Discussion Leader's Manual, American Foundation for Political Education, 1952 (Box 48, Folder 507)
  - World Politics Program pamphlet, 1956 (Box 48, Folder 508)
  - Readings in World Politics, Discussion Leader's Manual, American Foundation for Political Education, 1955 (Box 48, Folder 509)
  - Readings in World Politics, American Foundation for Political Education, Volumes One, Two, and Three, For Sessions I-X, 1953 (Box 48, Folder 510-512)
  - Headline Series Number 81, Foreign Policy Association - France: Setting or Rising Star, Saul K. Padover, 1950 May-June (Box 48, Folder 513)
  - Headline Series Number 82, Foreign Policy Association - Germany: Promise and Perils, Sigmund Neumann, 1950 July-August (Box 48, Folder 514)
  - Headline Series Number 90, Foreign Policy Association - The Story of US Foreign Policy, Dexter Perkins and James B. Conant, 1951 November-December (Box 48, Folder 515)
  - Headline Series Number 91, Foreign Policy Association - Africa: New Crises in the Making, Harold R. Isaacs and Emory Ross, 1952 January-February (Box 48, Folder 516)
  - Headline Series Number 98, Foreign Policy Association - The Emergence of Modern Egypt, John S. Badeau and Richard H. Nolte, 1953 March-April (Box 48, Folder 517)
  - Headline Series Number 99, Foreign Policy Association - China and the World, Tillman Durdin and Robert Aura Smith, 1953 May-June (Box 48, Folder 518)
  - Headline Series Number 100, Foreign Policy Association - The US and Latin America, Herbert L. Matthews and Lula T. Holmes, 1953 July-August (Box 49, Folder 519)
  - Headline Series Number 102, Foreign Policy Association - The New Japan, Royden Dangerfield, 1953 November-December (Box 49, Folder 520)
  - Headline Series Number 105, Foreign Policy Association - India Since Independence, Robert Trumball, 1954 May-June (Box 49, Folder 521)
  - Headline Series Number 106, Foreign Policy Association - Our Stake in World Trade, Isador Lubin and Forrest D. Murden, Jr., 1954 July-August (Box 49, Folder 522)
  - The Ways of Mankind Study: A Comparative Evaluation of Lecture and Discussion Group Methods in Liberal Adult Education, Richard J. Hill, Fund for Adult Education, 1959 (Box 49, Folder 523-525)
  - World Affairs Are Your Affairs: A Discussion Leader's Manual, 1952 (Box 49, Folder 526)
  - World Affairs Are Your Affairs pamphlet, 1952 (Box 49, Folder 527)
  - The World Map, National Geographic Magazine, 1951 December (Box 49, Folder 529)
  - World Affairs Are Your Affairs: An Adult Discussion, 1955 (Box 49, Folder 530)
  - How to Organize and Manage an Adult Discussion Project on "World Affairs Are YOUR Affairs', 1952 (Box 49, Folder 531)
  - World Affairs Are Your Affairs, First Edition, 1952 (Box 49, Folder 532)
  - World Affairs Are Your Affairs, Second Edition, 1953 (Box 49, Folder 533)
  - Readings in The Ways of Mankind, Discussion Leaders Guide, 1957 (Box 50, Folder 534)
  - Ways of Mankind: Thirteen Dramas of Peoples of the World and How They Live, 1954 (Box 50, Folder 535)
  - Readings in the Ways of Mankind 1, 1957 (Box 50, Folder 536)
  - Ways of Mankind: An Adult Discussion Program, 1955 (Box 50, Folder 537)
  - The Ways of Mankind: A Discussion Leader's Guide, 1958 (Box 50, Folder 538)
  - Parenthood in a Free Nation, Volume I: Basic Concepts for Parents, Ethel Kawin, 1963 (Box 50, Folder 539)
  - Parenthood in a Free Nation, Volume II: Early and Middle Childhood, Ethel Kawin, 1963 (Box 50, Folder 540)
  - Parenthood in a Free Nation, Volume III: Later Childhood and Adolescence, Ethel Kawin, 1963 (Box 50, Folder 541)
  - Parenthood in a Free Nation: A Manual for Leaders and Group Members, Parent Education Project, University of Chicago, Ethel Kawin, 1955 (Box 50, Folder 542)
  - Parenthood in a Free Nation: Readings for the Basic Course, University of Chicago Parent Education Project, 1956 (Box 51, Folder 543)
  - Transition and Tension in Southeast Asia - Invitation Pamphlet and Fact Sheet, undated (Box 51, Folder 544)
  - Transition and Tension in Southeast Asia: A Discussion Leader's Guide, 1957 (Box 51, Folder 545)
  - Transition and Tension in Southeast Asia, Nathaniel Peffer, 1957 (Box 51, Folder 546)
  - The Power to Govern: Notes for Discussion Leaders, 1957 (Box 51, Folder 547)
  - Democracy in America: Leader's Discussion & Reading Guide by George E. Probst, undated (Box 51, Folder 548)
  - Democracy in America: Discussion & Reading Guide by George E. Probst, 1962 (Box 51, Folder 549)
  - Democracy in America: Scripts of the Fourteen Dramatizations by Lister Sinclair and George E. Probst Based on the Classic Work by Alexis de Tocqueville, National Educational Television and Radio Center, 1962 (Box 51, Folder 550)
  - The Happy Republic: A Reader in Tocqueville's America, Edited and with Introductions by George E. Probst, 1962 (Box 51, Folder 551)
  - The First National Association of Educational Broadcasters (NAEB) TV Production Workshop For Educational Television, 1953 September (Box 51, Folder 552)
  - Selected Readings on Rising Influences in Central America: Residential Seminars on World Affairs, 1956 (Box 51, Folder 553)
  - Your Money and Your Life: Inflation, Deflation, and You, 1954 (Box 52, Folder 554)
  - Resource Statements For Use with the Study Discussion Program "Your Money and Your Life", undated (Box 52, Folder 555)
  - Los Angeles Television, May 23-29, 1951 by Dallas M. Smythe and Angus Campbell (2 copies), 1951 December (Box 52, Folder 556)
  - Chicago Summer Television, July 30-August 5, 1951 by Donald Horton, Hans O. Mauksch and Kurt Lang (Box 52, Folder 557)
  - New York Television, January 4-10, 1951-1952 by Dallas W. Smythe, 1952 August (Box 52, Folder 558)
  - Three Years of New York Television, 1951-1953 by Dallas Smythe, 1953 July (Box 52, Folder 559)
  - Four Years of New York Television, 1951-1954, The Purdue Opinion Panel, 1954 June (Box 52, Folder 560)
  - New Haven Television, May 15-21, 1952 by Dallas W. Smythe (2 copies), 1953 April (Box 52, Folder 561)
  - Freedom, Education, and the Fund: Essays and Addresses, 1946-1956, Robert M. Hutchins (Box 52, Folder 562)
  - Looking at Modern Art, 1959 (Box 53, Folder 563)
  - Metropolis: Values in Conflict, C. E. Elias, Jr., James Gillies, and Svend Riemer, Instructor and Discussion Leader's Manual, Leonard Freedman, 1964 (Box 53, Folder 564)
  - World Trade: A Discussion Leaders Guide for the First in a Series of Film-Discussion Programs on International Understanding, undated (Box 53, Folder 565)
  - World Trade: A Background Essay for One in a Series of Film-Discussion Programs on International Understanding, Eugene Staley, 1952 (Box 53, Folder 566)
  - Japan: A Background Essay for One in a Series of Film-Discussion Programs on International Understanding, 1952 (Box 53, Folder 567)
  - Japan: A Discussion Leaders Guide for the Third in a Series of Film-Discussion Programs on International Understanding, undated (Box 53, Folder 568)
  - China: A Discussion Leaders Guide for the Fourth in a Series of Film-Discussion Programs on International Understanding, undated (Box 53, Folder 569)
  - China: A Background Essay for One in a Series of Film-Discussion Programs on International Understanding, 1952 (Box 53, Folder 570)
  - Iran: A Discussion Leaders Guide for the Fifth in a Series of Film-Discussion Programs on International Understanding, undated (Box 53, Folder 571)
  - Iran: A Background Essay for One in a Series of Film-Discussion Programs on International Understanding, 1952 (Box 53, Folder 572)
  - Indonesia: A Discussion Leaders Guide for the Sixth in a Series of Film-Discussion Programs on International Understanding, undated (Box 53, Folder 573)
  - Indonesia: A Background Essay for One in a Series of Film-Discussion Programs on International Understanding, 1952 (Box 53, Folder 574)
  - Yugoslavia: A Discussion Leaders Guide for the Seventh in a Series of Film-Discussion Programs on International Understanding, undated (Box 53, Folder 575)
  - Yugoslavia: A Background Essay for One in a Series of Film-Discussion Programs on International Understanding, 1952 (Box 53, Folder 576)
  - Nigeria: A Background Essay for One in a Series of Film-Discussion Programs on International Understanding, 1952 (Box 53, Folder 577)
  - Nigeria: A Discussion Leaders Guide for the Eighth in a Series of Film-Discussion Programs on International Understanding, undated (Box 53, Folder 578)
  - Great Britain: A Discussion Leaders Guide for the Ninth in a Series of Film-Discussion Programs on International Understanding, undated (Box 53, Folder 579)
  - Great Britain: A Background Essay for One in a Series of Film-Discussion Programs on International Understanding, 1952 (Box 53, Folder 580)
  - India: A Background Essay for One in a Series of Film-Discussion Programs on International Understanding (2 copies), 1952 (Box 53, Folder 581)
  - India: A Discussion Leaders Guide for the Second in a Series of Film-Discussion Programs on International Understanding, undated (Box 53, Folder 582)
  - Values in Conflict, Metropolis: Creator or Destroyer: Utilization Manual, 1965 (Box 53, Folder 583)
  - You and Modern Art: A Series of Exploratory Adult Discussion Programs Prepared for the Experimental Discussion Project of the Fund for Adult Education, First Draft, Jules Langsner, 1953 April (Box 53, Folder 584-585)
  - Exploring the American Idea, 1953-1954: Announcing A Reading and Discussion Program in the New York Public Library brochure, undated (Box 54, Folder 586)
  - Announcing Adult Discussion Groups on Russian Foreign Policy brochure, undated (Box 54, Folder 587)
  - Our Growing America, Lawrence Senesh - Filmstrip Narrations, 1956 (Box 54, Folder 588)
  - This is Our Growing America, 1956 June 21; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 8, Reel AV 9444)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Access copy currently unavailable. Please contact an RAC archivist for further instruction.
  - Our Growing America - Educational Filmstrip, 1956; Filmstrip (Box 1, Reel AV 9444B)
  - Discussion Leader's Guide on Law and Justice, Experimental Discussion Project, The Fund for Adult Education, 1953 (?) (Box 54, Folder 589)
  - Law and Justice: Adult Discussion Series on the Nature of Human Law and Its Administration, Dr. Walter Goldschmidt, 1954 (Box 54, Folder 590)
  - Discovering Modern Poetry: Notes for the Leader, 1956 (Box 54, Folder 591)
  - Discovering Modern Poetry: A Series of Study and Discussion Programs for Adult Groups, 1956 (Box 54, Folder 592)
  - Discovering Modern Poetry: Some Suggestions About the Discussion, undated (Box 54, Folder 593)
  - Looking at Modern Painting: Slide Manual for Discussion Leaders, 1957 (Box 54, Folder 594)
    Includes a List of Illustrations for Looking at Modern Painting
  - Looking at Modern Painting: Some Suggestions About the Discussion, undated (Box 54, Folder 595)
  - Looking at Modern Painting: A Discussion Leader's Guide, 1958 (Box 54, Folder 596)
  - Looking at Pictures: A Guide to Intelligent Appreciation, Center for the Study of Liberal Education for Adults, 1955 (Box 54, Folder 597)
  - The Pocket Book of Modern Verse: English & American Poetry of the Last 100 Years From Walt Whitman to Dylan Thomas, An Anthology Edited by Oscar Williams, 1954 (Box 54, Folder 598)
  - The Waste Land and Other Poems, T. S. Eliot, 1934 (Box 54, Folder 599)
  - An Introduction to Economic Reasoning: A Manual for Discussion Group Participants and Leaders, Marshall A. Robinson and Herbert C. Morton, 1955 (Box 54, Folder 600)